Guide to the Turbese Lummis Fiske Papers, 1929-1948
Department of Special Collections
Turbese Lummis Fiske Papers,
1929-1948
Special Collections M0189
Fiske, Turbese Lummis.
0.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Restricted access; requires 24 hour paging period.
Provenance
Gift of Keith Lummis, l969.
Scope and Content
Typescripts and correspondence. Correspondence is almost solely literary, relating to works represented in the collection. Typescripts include plays and short stories.
Container List
- Section I: Works of Turbesé Lummis Fiske.
  - Untitled fragments, typescript and carbon typescript, 42 pp. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Chouans, a play., Autograph manuscript, partially typescript, 181 pp. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - A Friend Out Of the Darkness, Typescript, 27 pp. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Grampa Charley, Carbon typescript, 49 pp. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    (p. 1 of typescript missing).
  - The Little House, the Sacred Door, Typescript, 21 pp. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mahala stories. 5 different drafts: Typescript, 19 pp. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Typescript and carbon typescript, each 17 pp. (plus additional carbon copy of pp. 2-4, 6-9, 11, 12, 14, 15)
  - Carbon typescript, 28 pp.
  - Typescript, 34 pp. (entitled The Pattern Of Judgment)
  - Carbon typescript, 21 pp. (entitled The Unforgotten Shawl).
  - Michael Of the Point, Typescript, 27 pp. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - They Went To Buy a Grindstone, Carbon typescript, 22 pp. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Way Of the Cooky Jar, a comedy in three acts., Typescript with autograph corrections, 82 pp. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Section II: Correspondence.
  - General file, including letters to, from, or about, the following: (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Unidentified (15).
    - Abbott, George, 1938(3).
    - Adventure, 1935(2).
    - Argosy, 1930.
    - Barkow, -----, 1946.
    - Blair, Nan; See Folder 1 - 11.
    - Blue Book, 1929 - 1935(6).
    - Brandt, Erb, 1929 - 1930(4).
    - Chambrun, Jacques, 1934 - 1936(6).
    - Chappell, Delos, literary agency, 1937(2).
    - Clarke, Frances E., 1939.
    - Connelly, Marc, 1937.
    - Country Gentleman, 1937(3).
    - Crouse, Russell, 1941.
    - Curtis Brown, Limited; See Folder 1 - 12.
    - Darr, Mrs., 1946.
    - Dick, Sheldon, 1931 - 1932(3).
    - Doubleday, Doran and Company, 1929 - 1937(7).
    - Esquire, n.d.
    - Esteban, -----, 1946.
    - Federal Theatre Project, 1938(2).
    - Glassell, Steven A., 1946.
    - Golden, John, literary agency, 1937 - 1938(2).
    - Good Housekeeping, 1929 - 1939(9).
    - Haraszthy, -----, 1946.
    - Harper's Magazine, 1938.
    - Hearst Magazines, 1939.
    - Hilton, -----, 1929.
    - Hodge, Zabrah Preble, 1932.
    - Hopkins, Arthur, 1936(4).
    - Houghton, Mifflin Company, 1934 - 1939(3).
    - Knibbs, Olive, 1946(2).
    - Ladies' Home Journal; See Folder 1 - 13.
    - Lavender, Rosemary, 1945 - 1946(6).
    - Leussler, Harrison, 1946(2).
    - Liberty, 1938 - 1939(3).
    - Lotz, P. Henry, 1948.
    - Lummis, Jordan, 1946.
    - Lummis, Keith, 1946.
    - Mac, Sandy, 1946.
    - McCall Company, n.d., 1930(3).
    - McLain, Don, 1946(2).
    - Elisabeth Marbury, Inc., literary agency, 1936.
    - Marconel Corporation, 1937.
    - Martin, Belle, 1948(5).
    - Miles, -----, 1946.
    - Moore, Irving, n.d.
    - Brock Pemberton Little Theatre, 1938.
    - Pictorial Review, 1935(3).
    - The Playhouse Company Inc., 1939.
    - Popular magazine, 1930.
    - Purcell, -----, 1946.
    - Red Book, 1929 - 1930(3).
    - Redemann, -----, 1946.
    - Reynal and Hitchcock, 1941.
    - Rhodes, Rosemary, n.d.
    - San Diego Union, 1946.
    - The Saturday Evening Post; See Folder 1 - 14.
    - Schaffer, Bela, 1946(3).
    - Security First National Bank Of Los Angeles, 1932.
    - Stalcup,-----, 1946.
    - Teaboldt, Harrie and Mae, 1946.
    - The Theatre Guild, Incorporated, 1937.
    - Van der Veer, Judy, 1947 - 1948(3).
    - Wann, Louis, 1948.
    - Warner Brothers, 1933(2).
    - Westerberg, Iwar Sigurd, 1946.
    - Whittlesey House, 1948.
    - Woman's Home Companion; See Folder 1 - 15.
  - Blair, Nan, 1935 - 1939(20). (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Curtis Brown, Ltd., 1929 - 1939(13). (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ladies' Home Journal, 1929 - 1938(26). (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - The Saturday Evening Post, 1929 - 1939(18). (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Woman's Home Companion, 1932 - 1939(18). (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Section III: Works Of Others Than Turbesé Lummis Fiske.
  - Lummis, Charles Fletcher, poems, typescript, 20 pp. and index. (Box 1, Folder 16)